{
	"description": "Kanji for JLPT N4",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "お土産", "answers": [ "おみやげ" ], "comment": "present; souvenir" },
	{ "question": "お宅", "answers": [ "おたく" ], "comment": "your house; your home; your family\nyour husband\nyour organization\nyou (referring to someone of equal status with whom one is not especially close)" },
	{ "question": "お礼", "answers": [ "おれい" ], "comment": "thanks; gratitude\nmanners; etiquette\nbow\nreward; gift\nceremony; ritual" },
	{ "question": "お祝い", "answers": [ "おいわい" ], "comment": "congratulation; congratulations; celebration; festival; congratulatory gift" },
	{ "question": "お祭り", "answers": [ "おまつり" ], "comment": "festival; feast; carnival" },
	{ "question": "ご主人", "answers": [ "ごしゅじん" ], "comment": "your husband; her husband" },
	{ "question": "ご存じ", "answers": [ "ごぞんじ" ], "comment": "knowing\n(an) acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "再来月", "answers": [ "さらいげつ" ], "comment": "month after next" },
	{ "question": "再来週", "answers": [ "さらいしゅう" ], "comment": "week after next" },
	{ "question": "一度", "answers": [ "いちど" ], "comment": "once; one time; on one occasion\ntemporarily; for a moment\none degree; one tone; one musical interval" },
	{ "question": "上がる", "answers": [ "あがる" ], "comment": "to rise; to go up; to come up; to ascend; to be raised\nto enter (esp. from outdoors); to come in; to go in\nto enter (a school); to advance to the next grade\nto get out (of water); to come ashore\nto increase\nto improve; to make progress\nto be promoted; to advance\nto be made (of profit, etc.)\nto occur (esp. of a favourable result)\nto be adequate (to cover expenses, etc.)\nto be finished; to be done; to be over\n(of rain) to stop; to lift\nto stop (working properly); to cut out; to give out; to die\nto win (in a card game, etc.)\nto be spoken loudly\nto get stage fright\nto be offered (to the gods, etc.)\nto go; to visit\nto eat; to drink\nto be listed (as a candidate)\nto serve (in one's master's home)\nto go north\nindicates completion" },
	{ "question": "上る", "answers": [ "のぼる" ], "comment": "to rise; to go up; to come up; to ascend; to be raised\nto enter (esp. from outdoors); to come in; to go in\nto enter (a school); to advance to the next grade\nto get out (of water); to come ashore\nto increase\nto improve; to make progress\nto be promoted; to advance\nto be made (of profit, etc.)\nto occur (esp. of a favourable result)\nto be adequate (to cover expenses, etc.)\nto be finished; to be done; to be over\n(of rain) to stop; to lift\nto stop (working properly); to cut out; to give out; to die\nto win (in a card game, etc.)\nto be spoken loudly\nto get stage fright\nto be offered (to the gods, etc.)\nto go; to visit\nto eat; to drink\nto be listed (as a candidate)\nto serve (in one's master's home)\nto go north\nindicates completion\nto ascend; to go up; to climb\nto ascend (as a natural process, e.g. the sun); to rise\nto go to (the capital)\nto be promoted\nto add up to\nto advance (in price)\nto swim up (a river); to sail up\nto come up (on the agenda)" },
	{ "question": "下げる", "answers": [ "さげる" ], "comment": "to hang; to suspend; to wear (e.g. decoration)\nto lower; to reduce; to bring down\nto demote; to move back; to pull back\nto clear (plates); to remove (food, etc. from table or altar)" },
	{ "question": "下りる", "answers": [ "おりる" ], "comment": "to descend (e.g. a mountain); to go down; to come down\nto alight (e.g. from bus); to get off; to disembark; to dismount\nto step down; to retire; to give up; to quit\nto be granted; to be issued; to be given\nto form (of frost, dew, mist, etc.)\nto be passed (from the body; e.g. of a roundworm)" },
	{ "question": "下る", "answers": [ "くだる" ], "comment": "to come down; to go down; to fall; to drop; to sink; to get lower\nto hang; to dangle\nto move back; to step back; to withdraw; to retire\nto deteriorate; to fall off; to be downgraded\nto get closer to the present day\nto go south\nto descend; to go down; to come down\nto be handed down (of an order, judgment, etc.)\nto pass (of time)\nto surrender; to capitulate\n(often in neg. form) to be less than; to be inferior to\nto have the runs; to have diarrhea\nto pass (in stool); to be discharged from the body" },
	{ "question": "下宿", "answers": [ "げしゅく" ], "comment": "boarding; lodging; boarding house" },
	{ "question": "下着", "answers": [ "したぎ" ], "comment": "underwear" },
	{ "question": "不便", "answers": [ "ふべん" ], "comment": "inconvenience; inexpediency; unhandiness\npity; compassion" },
	{ "question": "世界", "answers": [ "せかい" ], "comment": "the world; society; the universe\nsphere; circle; world\nrenowned; world-famous; well-known outside of Japan\nrealm governed by one Buddha; space" },
	{ "question": "両方", "answers": [ "りょうほう" ], "comment": "both; both sides; both parties" },
	{ "question": "中学校", "answers": [ "ちゅうがっこう" ], "comment": "junior high school; middle school; lower secondary school" },
	{ "question": "久しぶり", "answers": [ "ひさしぶり" ], "comment": "a long time (since the last time); it's been a while (since I last saw, mailed, etc., you)" },
	{ "question": "乗り物", "answers": [ "のりもの" ], "comment": "vehicle; conveyance; transport\nride (playground, fair, carnival); playground facility" },
	{ "question": "予定", "answers": [ "よてい" ], "comment": "plans; arrangement; schedule; program; programme; expectation; estimate" },
	{ "question": "予約", "answers": [ "よやく" ], "comment": "reservation; appointment; booking; advance order\ncontract; subscription; pledge\nprogramming (e.g. a device); setting (e.g. a timer)" },
	{ "question": "予習", "answers": [ "よしゅう" ], "comment": "preparation for a lesson" },
	{ "question": "事務所", "answers": [ "じむしょ" ], "comment": "office" },
	{ "question": "事故", "answers": [ "じこ" ], "comment": "accident; incident; trouble\ncircumstances; reasons" },
	{ "question": "二階建て", "answers": [ "にかいだて" ], "comment": "two-storied building" },
	{ "question": "亡くなる", "answers": [ "なくなる" ], "comment": "to die" },
	{ "question": "交通", "answers": [ "こうつう" ], "comment": "traffic; transportation; communication; exchange (of ideas, etc.); intercourse" },
	{ "question": "人口", "answers": [ "じんこう" ], "comment": "population\ncommon talk" },
	{ "question": "人形", "answers": [ "にんぎょう" ], "comment": "doll; puppet; figure" },
	{ "question": "今夜", "answers": [ "こんや" ], "comment": "this evening; tonight" },
	{ "question": "今度", "answers": [ "こんど" ], "comment": "this time; now\nnext time; another time; shortly; soon\nrecently; previous; last" },
	{ "question": "仕方", "answers": [ "しかた" ], "comment": "way; method; means; resource; course" },
	{ "question": "付く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "to be attached; to be connected with; to adhere; to stick; to cling\nto remain imprinted; to scar; to stain; to dye\nto bear (fruit, interest, etc.)\nto be acquired (of a habit, ability, etc.); to increase (of strength, etc.)\nto take root\nto accompany; to attend; to follow; to study with\nto side with; to belong to\nto possess; to haunt\nto be lit; to be lighted\nto be settled; to be resolved; to be decided\nto be given (of a name, price, etc.)\nto be sensed; to be perceived\nto be lucky\nto become (a state, condition, etc.)\nto become (a state, condition, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "代わり", "answers": [ "かわり" ], "comment": "substitute; replacement; substituting; replacing\nstand-in; proxy; alternate; deputy; relief; successor\ncompensation; exchange; return\nsecond helping; another cup; seconds\nupcoming program; upcoming programme\nsubstitute for ..." },
	{ "question": "以上", "answers": [ "いじょう" ], "comment": "not less than; ... and more; ... and upwards\nbeyond ... (e.g. one's means); further (e.g. nothing further to say); more than ... (e.g. cannot pay more than that)\nabove-mentioned; foregoing\nsince ...; seeing that ...\nthis is all; that is the end; the end" },
	{ "question": "以下", "answers": [ "いか" ], "comment": "not exceeding; and downward; ... and below\nbelow (e.g. standard); under (e.g. a level)\nthe below-mentioned; the following; the rest" },
	{ "question": "以内", "answers": [ "いない" ], "comment": "within; inside of; less than" },
	{ "question": "以外", "answers": [ "いがい" ], "comment": "with the exception of; excepting" },
	{ "question": "会場", "answers": [ "かいじょう" ], "comment": "assembly hall; meeting place; venue; grounds" },
	{ "question": "会話", "answers": [ "かいわ" ], "comment": "conversation" },
	{ "question": "会議", "answers": [ "かいぎ" ], "comment": "meeting; conference; session; assembly; council; convention; congress" },
	{ "question": "会議室", "answers": [ "かいぎしつ" ], "comment": "conference room; council room" },
	{ "question": "伝える", "answers": [ "つたえる" ], "comment": "to convey; to report; to transmit; to communicate; to tell; to impart; to propagate; to teach; to bequeath" },
	{ "question": "似る", "answers": [ "にる" ], "comment": "to resemble; to look like; to take after\nto be similar (in status, condition, etc.); to be close; to be alike; to be like" },
	{ "question": "住所", "answers": [ "じゅうしょ" ], "comment": "address (e.g. of house); residence; domicile" },
	{ "question": "例えば", "answers": [ "たとえば" ], "comment": "for example; for instance; e.g." },
	{ "question": "倍", "answers": [ "ばい" ], "comment": "twice; double\ntimes; -fold" },
	{ "question": "倒れる", "answers": [ "たおれる" ], "comment": "to fall; to collapse; to drop; to fall senseless\nto be forced to bed (by illness, etc.)\nto die\nto go bankrupt; to be ruined; to have a bad debt\nto be defeated (in a game)\nto fall (of governments, dictators, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "優しい", "answers": [ "やさしい" ], "comment": "tender; kind; gentle; graceful; affectionate; amiable" },
	{ "question": "先輩", "answers": [ "せんぱい" ], "comment": "senior (at work or school); superior; elder; older graduate; progenitor; old-timer" },
	{ "question": "光", "answers": [ "ひかり" ], "comment": "light\nillumination; ray; beam; gleam; glow\nhappiness; hope\ninfluence; power\nvision; eyesight" },
	{ "question": "光る", "answers": [ "ひかる" ], "comment": "to shine; to glitter; to be bright" },
	{ "question": "入学", "answers": [ "にゅうがく" ], "comment": "entry to school or university; matriculation; enrolment (in university, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "入院", "answers": [ "にゅういん" ], "comment": "hospitalization; hospitalisation" },
	{ "question": "八百屋", "answers": [ "やおや" ], "comment": "greengrocer" },
	{ "question": "公務員", "answers": [ "こうむいん" ], "comment": "government worker; public servant; civil servant" },
	{ "question": "具合", "answers": [ "ぐあい" ], "comment": "condition; state; manner; health" },
	{ "question": "内", "answers": [ "うち" ], "comment": "inside; within\nwhile\namong; amongst; between\nwe (referring to one's in-group, e.g. company, etc.); our\nmy spouse\nimperial palace grounds\nemperor\nI (primarily used by women and children); me\ninside; within" },
	{ "question": "写す", "answers": [ "うつす" ], "comment": "to transcribe; to duplicate; to reproduce; to imitate; to trace\nto describe\nto film; to picture; to photograph" },
	{ "question": "冷える", "answers": [ "ひえる" ], "comment": "to grow cold (from room temperature, e.g. in refrigerator); to get chilly; to cool down" },
	{ "question": "冷たい", "answers": [ "つめたい" ], "comment": "cold (to the touch); chilly; icy; freezing\ncoldhearted; unfeeling" },
	{ "question": "別", "answers": [ "べつ" ], "comment": "distinction; difference; different; another; particular; separate; extra; exception\nlord (hereditary title for imperial descendants in outlying regions)" },
	{ "question": "別れる", "answers": [ "わかれる" ], "comment": "to part (usu. of people); to part from; to part with; to be apart from\nto separate (of a couple); to break up; to divorce\nto lose (e.g. one's mother); to be bereaved" },
	{ "question": "利用", "answers": [ "りよう" ], "comment": "use; utilization; utilisation; application" },
	{ "question": "力", "answers": [ "ちから" ], "comment": "force; strength; might; vigour (vigor); energy\ncapability; ability; proficiency; capacity; faculty\nefficacy; effect\neffort; endeavours (endeavors); exertions\npower; authority; influence; good offices; agency\nsupport; help; aid; assistance\nstress; emphasis\nmeans; resources\nthe strength of ... people; the strength of ... men" },
	{ "question": "勉強", "answers": [ "べんきょう" ], "comment": "study\ndiligence\ndiscount; reduction" },
	{ "question": "動く", "answers": [ "うごく" ], "comment": "to move; to stir; to shift; to shake; to swing\nto operate; to run; to go; to work\nto be touched; to be influenced\nto change; to vary; to fluctuate; to waver\ncertain; factual\nto be transferred" },
	{ "question": "動物園", "answers": [ "どうぶつえん" ], "comment": "zoo; zoological gardens" },
	{ "question": "勝つ", "answers": [ "かつ" ], "comment": "to win; to gain victory" },
	{ "question": "包む", "answers": [ "つつむ", "くるむ" ], "comment": "to wrap up; to tuck in; to pack; to do up; to cover with; to dress in\nto conceal; to hide; to be engulfed in; to be enveloped by" },
	{ "question": "医学", "answers": [ "いがく" ], "comment": "medical science; medicine" },
	{ "question": "十分", "answers": [ "じゅうぶん", "じゅっぷん", "じっぷん" ], "comment": "10 minutes\nplenty; enough; sufficient; satisfactory; adequate\ndivision into ten\nperfectly; thoroughly; fully; in full" },
	{ "question": "卒業", "answers": [ "そつぎょう" ], "comment": "graduation; completion (e.g. of a course)\noutgrowing something; moving on" },
	{ "question": "危険", "answers": [ "きけん" ], "comment": "danger; peril; hazard\nrisk" },
	{ "question": "原因", "answers": [ "げんいん" ], "comment": "cause; origin; source" },
	{ "question": "厳しい", "answers": [ "きびしい" ], "comment": "severe; strict; rigid; unsparing; relentless\nintense (e.g. cold); harsh; tough" },
	{ "question": "参る", "answers": [ "まいる" ], "comment": "to go; to come; to call\nto be defeated; to collapse; to die\nto be annoyed; to be nonplussed\nto be madly in love\nto visit (shrine, grave)" },
	{ "question": "反対", "answers": [ "はんたい" ], "comment": "opposition; resistance; antagonism; hostility; objection; dissension\nreverse; opposite; vice versa; contrast" },
	{ "question": "取り替える", "answers": [ "とりかえる" ], "comment": "to exchange; to replace" },
	{ "question": "受ける", "answers": [ "うける" ], "comment": "to receive; to get\nto catch (e.g. a ball)\nto be struck by (wind, waves, sunlight, etc.)\nto sustain (damage); to incur (a loss); to suffer (an injury); to feel (influence)\nto undergo (e.g. surgery); to take (a test); to accept (a challenge)\nto be given (e.g. life, talent)\nto follow; to succeed; to be descended from\nto face (south, etc.)\nto be modified by\nto obtain (a pawned item, etc.) by paying a fee\nto be well-received; to become popular; to go down well\nto be funny; to be humorous" },
	{ "question": "受付", "answers": [ "うけつけ" ], "comment": "reception (desk); information desk\nreceipt; acceptance" },
	{ "question": "召し上がる", "answers": [ "めしあがる" ], "comment": "to eat; to drink" },
	{ "question": "台風", "answers": [ "たいふう" ], "comment": "typhoon; hurricane" },
	{ "question": "合う", "answers": [ "あう" ], "comment": "to come together; to merge; to unite; to meet\nto fit; to match; to suit; to agree with; to be correct\nto be profitable; to be equitable\nto do ... to each other; to do ... together" },
	{ "question": "向かう", "answers": [ "むかう" ], "comment": "to face\nto go towards; to head towards" },
	{ "question": "君", "answers": [ "きみ" ], "comment": "you; buddy; pal\nmonarch; ruler; sovereign; (one's) master\nMr (junior); master; boy\nsuffix appended to somebody else's family members\nyou" },
	{ "question": "周り", "answers": [ "まわり" ], "comment": "circumference; girth\nsurroundings; neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity" },
	{ "question": "味", "answers": [ "あじ" ], "comment": "flavor; flavour; taste\ncharm; style\nexperience\nsmart; clever; witty; strange\n(sense of) taste\ncounter for food, drink, medicine, etc." },
	{ "question": "品物", "answers": [ "しなもの" ], "comment": "goods; article; thing" },
	{ "question": "喜ぶ", "answers": [ "よろこぶ" ], "comment": "to be delighted; to be glad; to be pleased\nto congratulate\nto gratefully accept" },
	{ "question": "回る", "answers": [ "まわる" ], "comment": "to go around\nto return\nto surround\nto concern (usu. of disputes)\nto turn; to revolve\nto visit several places\nto function well\nto pass a certain time\nto wander around\nto go around" },
	{ "question": "困る", "answers": [ "こまる" ], "comment": "to be troubled; to be worried; to be bothered; to be embarrassed; to be stumped" },
	{ "question": "図書館", "answers": [ "としょかん" ], "comment": "library" },
	{ "question": "固い", "answers": [ "かたい" ], "comment": "hard; solid; tough\nstiff; tight; wooden; unpolished (e.g. writing)\nstrong; firm (not viscous or easily moved)\nsafe; steady; honest; steadfast\nobstinate; stubborn\nbookish; formal; stuffy" },
	{ "question": "国際", "answers": [ "こくさい" ], "comment": "international" },
	{ "question": "地理", "answers": [ "ちり" ], "comment": "geography" },
	{ "question": "地震", "answers": [ "じしん" ], "comment": "earthquake" },
	{ "question": "坂", "answers": [ "さか" ], "comment": "slope; hill" },
	{ "question": "場合", "answers": [ "ばあい" ], "comment": "case; situation" },
	{ "question": "場所", "answers": [ "ばしょ" ], "comment": "place; location; spot; position\nroom; space\nbasho; wrestling tournament" },
	{ "question": "増える", "answers": [ "ふえる" ], "comment": "to increase; to multiply" },
	{ "question": "声", "answers": [ "こえ" ], "comment": "voice" },
	{ "question": "売り場", "answers": [ "うりば" ], "comment": "place where things are sold; point of sale; POS; sales floor; counter (in shop)\nfavorable time to sell; good time to sell" },
	{ "question": "変", "answers": [ "へん" ], "comment": "strange; odd; peculiar; weird; curious; queer; eccentric; funny; suspicious; fishy\nunexpected\nchange\nincident; disturbance; disaster; accident\nflat" },
	{ "question": "変える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to change; to alter; to transform; to convert; to turn; to vary\nto reform; to revise; to amend" },
	{ "question": "変わる", "answers": [ "かわる" ], "comment": "to change; to be transformed; to be altered; to vary\nto move to\nto be different; to be uncommon; to be unusual" },
	{ "question": "夢", "answers": [ "ゆめ" ], "comment": "dream" },
	{ "question": "大事", "answers": [ "だいじ", "おおごと" ], "comment": "important; valuable; serious matter\nsafe (Tochigi dialect); OK" },
	{ "question": "大体", "answers": [ "だいたい" ], "comment": "outline; main point; gist\ngeneral; substantially; approximately; about\nin the first place; to begin with; from the start" },
	{ "question": "大分", "answers": [ "だいぶ", "だいぶん" ], "comment": "considerably; greatly; a lot" },
	{ "question": "大学生", "answers": [ "だいがくせい" ], "comment": "university student; college student" },
	{ "question": "天気予報", "answers": [ "てんきよほう" ], "comment": "weather forecast; weather report" },
	{ "question": "太る", "answers": [ "ふとる" ], "comment": "to grow fat (stout, plump); to become fat; to gain weight" },
	{ "question": "夫", "answers": [ "おっと" ], "comment": "my dear; dear; honey\ngarnish (esp. one served with sashimi)\nembellishment\nhusband\nmale; man\nhusband\nthat\nhe; she; that person" },
	{ "question": "失敗", "answers": [ "しっぱい" ], "comment": "failure; mistake; blunder" },
	{ "question": "女性", "answers": [ "じょせい" ], "comment": "woman; female\nfeminine gender" },
	{ "question": "妻", "answers": [ "つま" ], "comment": "wife\nmy dear; dear; honey\ngarnish (esp. one served with sashimi)\nembellishment\nfemale; woman\nwife\none's wife\nedge; tip; end\ngable wall\ngable" },
	{ "question": "始める", "answers": [ "はじめる" ], "comment": "to start; to begin; to commence; to initiate; to originate\nto open (e.g. a store); to start up; to establish (business. etc.)\nto start ...; to begin to ..." },
	{ "question": "娘", "answers": [ "むすめ" ], "comment": "(my) daughter\ngirl (i.e. a young, unmarried woman)" },
	{ "question": "字", "answers": [ "じ", "あざ" ], "comment": "section of village\ncharacter (i.e. kanji)\nhand-writing; penmanship\nthe ... word (i.e. \"the L word\" = \"love\")\nChinese courtesy name (name formerly given to adult Chinese men, used in place of their given name in formal situations)\nnickname\nsection of a village" },
	{ "question": "安全", "answers": [ "あんぜん" ], "comment": "safety\nsecurity" },
	{ "question": "安心", "answers": [ "あんしん" ], "comment": "relief; peace of mind\nobtaining peace of mind through faith or ascetic practice" },
	{ "question": "客", "answers": [ "きゃく" ], "comment": "guest; visitor\ncustomer; client; shopper; spectator; audience; tourist; sightseer; passenger\nvisitor from afar; guest\nvisitor from afar\njoy-bringing spirit from the divine realms" },
	{ "question": "家内", "answers": [ "かない" ], "comment": "(my) wife\ninside the home; one's family" },
	{ "question": "寄る", "answers": [ "よる" ], "comment": "to approach; to draw near; to come near; to be close to\nto gather (in one place); to come together; to meet\nto stop by (while on one's way to another place); to drop by; to make a short visit\nto grow old; to grow high (number, etc.)\nto grow (wrinkly)\nto lean against; to recline on\nto push one's opponent while holding their belt\nto decide on a price and come to a deal\nto be swayed by (a person); to yield to" },
	{ "question": "寝坊", "answers": [ "ねぼう" ], "comment": "sleeping in late; oversleeping\nlate riser; sleepyhead" },
	{ "question": "寺", "answers": [ "てら" ], "comment": "temple (Buddhist)\ncounter for temples" },
	{ "question": "将来", "answers": [ "しょうらい" ], "comment": "future (usually near); prospects" },
	{ "question": "小学校", "answers": [ "しょうがっこう" ], "comment": "primary school; elementary school; grade school" },
	{ "question": "小説", "answers": [ "しょうせつ" ], "comment": "novel; (short) story" },
	{ "question": "小鳥", "answers": [ "ことり" ], "comment": "small bird; songbird\nbirdie; dickeybird; dickybird" },
	{ "question": "届ける", "answers": [ "とどける" ], "comment": "to deliver; to forward; to send\nto report; to notify; to file notice (to the authorities); to give notice; to register" },
	{ "question": "屋上", "answers": [ "おくじょう" ], "comment": "rooftop" },
	{ "question": "島", "answers": [ "しま" ], "comment": "island\nterritory (of a prostitute, organized crime gang, etc.); turf\nIsland\ninsula; island; islet" },
	{ "question": "工場", "answers": [ "こうじょう", "こうば" ], "comment": "factory; plant; mill; workshop" },
	{ "question": "工業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "(manufacturing) industry" },
	{ "question": "差し上げる", "answers": [ "さしあげる" ], "comment": "to give; to offer\nto lift up; to hold up; to raise" },
	{ "question": "市", "answers": [ "し", "いち" ], "comment": "market; fair\ncity" },
	{ "question": "市民", "answers": [ "しみん" ], "comment": "citizen; citizenry; public\ncity inhabitant; townspeople\nbourgeoisie; middle class" },
	{ "question": "布団", "answers": [ "ふとん" ], "comment": "futon (quilted Japanese-style mattress laid out on the floor)\nround cushion used for Zen meditation (traditionally made of woven bulrush leaves)" },
	{ "question": "席", "answers": [ "せき" ], "comment": "seat\nlocation (of a gathering, etc.); place\nposition; post\nwoven mat (esp. one made of straw)\nseat" },
	{ "question": "帰り", "answers": [ "かえり" ], "comment": "return; coming back" },
	{ "question": "店員", "answers": [ "てんいん" ], "comment": "shop assistant; employee; clerk; salesperson" },
	{ "question": "建てる", "answers": [ "たてる" ], "comment": "to build; to construct" },
	{ "question": "引き出し", "answers": [ "ひきだし" ], "comment": "drawer\nwithdrawal; drawing out\nvariety of knowledge and experience useful for handling things impromptu" },
	{ "question": "引っ越す", "answers": [ "ひっこす" ], "comment": "to move (house); to change residence" },
	{ "question": "形", "answers": [ "かたち", "かた", "なり" ], "comment": "form; shape; figure\nvisage\nshape; appearance\ncollateral\nobverse of an old \"zeni\" coin\nstyle; way; shape; form; appearance; state" },
	{ "question": "役に立つ", "answers": [ "やくにたつ" ], "comment": "to be helpful; to be useful" },
	{ "question": "彼", "answers": [ "かれ" ], "comment": "that (indicating something distant from both speaker and listener (in space, time or psychologically), or something understood without naming it directly)\nthat person (used to refer to one's equals or inferiors)\nover there\ndown there (i.e. one's genitals)\nperiod; menses\nhey (expression of surprise, suspicion, etc.); huh?; eh?\nthat (something mentioned before which is distant psychologically or in terms of time)\nhe; him\nhis\nboyfriend" },
	{ "question": "彼女", "answers": [ "かのじょ" ], "comment": "she; her\nher\ngirlfriend; sweetheart" },
	{ "question": "復習", "answers": [ "ふくしゅう" ], "comment": "review; revision" },
	{ "question": "心", "answers": [ "こころ", "しん" ], "comment": "mind; heart; spirit\nthe meaning of a phrase (riddle, etc.)\nheart; mind\nspirit; vitality; inner strength\nChinese \"Heart\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\nfriend" },
	{ "question": "必ず", "answers": [ "かならず" ], "comment": "always; without exception; necessarily; certainly; without fail; positively; invariably" },
	{ "question": "必要", "answers": [ "ひつよう" ], "comment": "necessary; needed; essential; indispensable\nnecessity; need; requirement" },
	{ "question": "忘れ物", "answers": [ "わすれもの" ], "comment": "lost article; something forgotten" },
	{ "question": "怒る", "answers": [ "おこる", "いかる" ], "comment": "to get angry; to get mad\nto tell someone off; to scold\nto be angular; to be square" },
	{ "question": "怖い", "answers": [ "こわい" ], "comment": "scary; frightening; eerie; dreadful\n(I'm) afraid" },
	{ "question": "思い出す", "answers": [ "おもいだす" ], "comment": "to recall; to remember; to recollect" },
	{ "question": "思う", "answers": [ "おもう" ], "comment": "to think; to consider; to believe\nto think (of doing); to plan (to do)\nto judge; to assess; to regard\nto imagine; to suppose; to dream\nto expect; to look forward to\nto feel; to desire; to want\nto recall; to remember" },
	{ "question": "急", "answers": [ "きゅう" ], "comment": "urgent; sudden; abrupt\nsharp; steep; precipitous\nrapid; swift; fast\nemergency; crisis\nhurrying; haste\n(in gagaku or noh) end of a song" },
	{ "question": "急ぐ", "answers": [ "いそぐ" ], "comment": "to hurry; to rush; to hasten; to make something happen sooner" },
	{ "question": "急行", "answers": [ "きゅうこう" ], "comment": "moving at high speed\nexpress (e.g. train that bypasses many stations)" },
	{ "question": "恥ずかしい", "answers": [ "はずかしい" ], "comment": "shy; ashamed; embarrassed\ndisgraceful; shameful" },
	{ "question": "息子", "answers": [ "むすこ" ], "comment": "son\npenis" },
	{ "question": "悲しい", "answers": [ "かなしい" ], "comment": "sad; sorrowful" },
	{ "question": "意見", "answers": [ "いけん" ], "comment": "opinion; view; comment" },
	{ "question": "慣れる", "answers": [ "なれる" ], "comment": "to get used to; to grow accustomed to; to become familiar with\nto become skilled in; to become experienced at\nto become tame; to become domesticated" },
	{ "question": "戦争", "answers": [ "せんそう" ], "comment": "war" },
	{ "question": "戻る", "answers": [ "もどる" ], "comment": "to turn back (e.g. half-way)\nto return; to go back\nto recover (e.g. something lost); to be returned\nto rebound; to spring back\nto go against; to act contrary to; to deviate from; to oppose" },
	{ "question": "手伝う", "answers": [ "てつだう" ], "comment": "to help; to assist; to aid\nto contribute to; to be a factor in" },
	{ "question": "手袋", "answers": [ "てぶくろ" ], "comment": "glove; mitten; mitt" },
	{ "question": "打つ", "answers": [ "うつ", "ぶつ" ], "comment": "to hit; to strike; to knock; to beat; to punch; to slap; to tap; to bang; to clap; to pound\nto strike (noon, etc.); to sound (cymbals, etc.); to beat (a drum, etc.)\nto beat (rhythmically, e.g. pulse, waves, etc.)\nto move; to impress; to touch\nto drive in; to hammer in; to put in; to inject\nto type; to send; to transmit\nto insert; to write in; to mark\nto make (noodles, etc.); to prepare\nto till (soil)\nto sprinkle; to throw; to cast\nto do; to carry out; to play; to perform; to engage in (gambling, etc.)\nto pay (a deposit, etc.)\nto visit (on a pilgrimage)\nto line (a coat)\nto bind (a criminal)\nto hit (a person); to strike; to beat" },
	{ "question": "払う", "answers": [ "はらう" ], "comment": "to pay (e.g. money, bill)\nto brush off; to wipe away; to clear away; to dust off; to cut off (e.g. branches)\nto drive away (e.g. one's competitors)\nto sell off (something unneeded); to dispose of\nto pay (e.g. attention); to show (e.g. respect, concern)\nto make (e.g. effort, sacrifice); to expend; to exert\nto move out (of one's own place); to vacate\nto sweep (e.g. one's legs); to knock aside\nto make a sweeping stroke (in Japanese calligraphy)\nto reset (an abacus)" },
	{ "question": "技術", "answers": [ "ぎじゅつ" ], "comment": "technology; engineering\ntechnique; skill\nart; craft" },
	{ "question": "投げる", "answers": [ "なげる" ], "comment": "to throw; to cast away\nto face defeat; to give up" },
	{ "question": "折る", "answers": [ "おる" ], "comment": "to break; to fracture; to break off; to snap off; to pick (e.g. flowers)\nto fold; to bend\nto make (origami)\nto interrupt; to end" },
	{ "question": "折れる", "answers": [ "おれる" ], "comment": "to break; to be broken; to snap; to fracture\nto be folded\nto give in; to back down; to yield; to submit\nto turn (a corner)" },
	{ "question": "押し入れ", "answers": [ "おしいれ" ], "comment": "closet" },
	{ "question": "拾う", "answers": [ "ひろう" ], "comment": "to pick up; to find; to gather" },
	{ "question": "指", "answers": [ "ゆび" ], "comment": "finger; toe; digit\nbetween (e.g. two people); face to face\nhindrance; impediment\narrhythmic section of recitative in noh music\nprefix used for stress or emphasis\ncounter for traditional dance songs" },
	{ "question": "指輪", "answers": [ "ゆびわ" ], "comment": "(finger) ring" },
	{ "question": "掛ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "to hang (e.g. picture); to hoist (e.g. sail); to raise (e.g. flag)\nto sit\nto take (time, money); to expend (money, time, etc.)\nto make (a call)\nto multiply\nto secure (e.g. lock)\nto put on (glasses, etc.)\nto cover\nto burden someone\nto apply (insurance)\nto turn on (an engine, etc.); to set (a dial, an alarm clock, etc.)\nto put an effect (spell, anaesthetic, etc.) on\nto hold an emotion for (pity, hope, etc.)\nto bind\nto pour (or sprinkle, spray, etc.) onto\nto argue (in court); to deliberate (in a meeting); to present (e.g. idea to a conference, etc.)\nto increase further\nto catch (in a trap, etc.)\nto set atop\nto erect (a makeshift building)\nto hold (a play, festival, etc.)\nto wager; to bet; to risk; to stake; to gamble\nto be partway doing ...; to begin (but not complete) ...; to be about to ...\nindicates (verb) is being directed to (someone)" },
	{ "question": "探す", "answers": [ "さがす" ], "comment": "to search (for something desired, needed); to look for\nto search (for something lost); to seek (a suspect in a crime)" },
	{ "question": "故障", "answers": [ "こしょう" ], "comment": "breakdown; failure; fault; accident; out of order\ndamage; hurt\nobjection; protest" },
	{ "question": "教会", "answers": [ "きょうかい" ], "comment": "church" },
	{ "question": "教育", "answers": [ "きょういく" ], "comment": "training; education" },
	{ "question": "数学", "answers": [ "すうがく" ], "comment": "mathematics; arithmetic" },
	{ "question": "文化", "answers": [ "ぶんか" ], "comment": "culture; civilization; civilisation\nBunka era (1804.2.11-1818.4.22)" },
	{ "question": "文学", "answers": [ "ぶんがく" ], "comment": "literature" },
	{ "question": "文法", "answers": [ "ぶんぽう" ], "comment": "grammar; syntax" },
	{ "question": "新聞社", "answers": [ "しんぶんしゃ" ], "comment": "newspaper company" },
	{ "question": "旅館", "answers": [ "りょかん" ], "comment": "ryokan; Japanese-style lodging, usu. professionally-run" },
	{ "question": "日", "answers": [ "ひ", "にち" ], "comment": "day; days\nsun; sunshine; sunlight\ncase (esp. unfortunate); event\nSunday\nday (of the month)\ncounter for days\nJapan\nday of month\ncounter for days" },
	{ "question": "日記", "answers": [ "にっき" ], "comment": "diary; journal" },
	{ "question": "明日", "answers": [ "あした", "あす" ], "comment": "tomorrow\nnear future" },
	{ "question": "昔", "answers": [ "むかし" ], "comment": "olden days; former" },
	{ "question": "星", "answers": [ "ほし" ], "comment": "star; any light-emitting (or reflecting) heavenly body (except for the sun and the moon)\noffender; perpetrator\nstar point (in go); hoshi; intersection marked with a dot\ncircular symbol (said to be shaped like a shining star)\nbullseye\none's star (out of the nine stars); the star that determines one's fate\nsmall dot; spot\npoint; score\nChinese \"star\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\nSingapore" },
	{ "question": "昼休み", "answers": [ "ひるやすみ" ], "comment": "lunch break; noon recess; noon rest period" },
	{ "question": "昼間", "answers": [ "ひるま" ], "comment": "daytime; during the day; time from sunrise until sunset; diurnal period" },
	{ "question": "時代", "answers": [ "じだい" ], "comment": "period; epoch; era; age\nthe times; those days\noldness; ancientness; antiquity\nantique; period piece" },
	{ "question": "普通", "answers": [ "ふつう" ], "comment": "general; ordinary; usual\nnormally; generally; usually\nlocal train; train that stops at every station" },
	{ "question": "景色", "answers": [ "けしき" ], "comment": "scenery; scene; landscape" },
	{ "question": "暮れる", "answers": [ "くれる" ], "comment": "to get dark\nto end; to come to an end; to close; to run out\nto be sunk (e.g. in despair); to be lost" },
	{ "question": "最初", "answers": [ "さいしょ" ], "comment": "beginning; outset; first; onset" },
	{ "question": "最後", "answers": [ "さいご" ], "comment": "last; end; conclusion; latest; most recent\nno sooner than; right after (often having negative consequences)\none's final moments" },
	{ "question": "最近", "answers": [ "さいきん" ], "comment": "most recent; these days; right now; recently; nowadays" },
	{ "question": "木綿", "answers": [ "もめん" ], "comment": "cotton (material)\nred silk-cotton tree (Bombax ceiba)\nstring made of cut steamed, soaked mulberry bark fibers" },
	{ "question": "机", "answers": [ "つくえ" ], "comment": "desk" },
	{ "question": "林", "answers": [ "はやし" ], "comment": "woods; forest; copse; thicket\nbunch; line (of something); collection" },
	{ "question": "枝", "answers": [ "えだ" ], "comment": "branch; bow; bough; twig; limb\ncounter for long, thin things (i.e. swords)" },
	{ "question": "柔らかい", "answers": [ "やわらかい" ], "comment": "soft; tender; limp; limber\ngentle; mild\ninformal; lighter" },
	{ "question": "柔道", "answers": [ "じゅうどう" ], "comment": "judo" },
	{ "question": "校長", "answers": [ "こうちょう" ], "comment": "principal; headmaster" },
	{ "question": "森", "answers": [ "もり" ], "comment": "forest\nshrine grove" },
	{ "question": "植える", "answers": [ "うえる" ], "comment": "to plant; to grow; to raise\nto insert; to transplant; to implant; to set (type)\nto inoculate (e.g. an infectious agent)\nto instill (idea, value, etc.); to instil; to inculcate" },
	{ "question": "楽しみ", "answers": [ "たのしみ" ], "comment": "enjoyment; pleasure; diversion; amusement; hobby\nanticipation; looking forward to" },
	{ "question": "楽しむ", "answers": [ "たのしむ" ], "comment": "to enjoy (oneself)" },
	{ "question": "機会", "answers": [ "きかい" ], "comment": "chance; opportunity" },
	{ "question": "止む", "answers": [ "やむ" ], "comment": "to cease; to stop; to be over" },
	{ "question": "止める", "answers": [ "とめる", "やめる", "とどめる" ], "comment": "to stop; to turn off\nto park\nto prevent; to suppress (a cough); to hold back (tears); to hold (one's breath); to relieve (pain)\nto stop (someone from doing something); to dissuade; to forbid; to prohibit\nto notice; to be aware of; to concentrate on; to pay attention to; to remember; to bear in mind\nto fix (in place); to fasten; to tack; to pin; to nail; to button; to staple\nto detain; to keep in custody\nto stop (an activity); to cease; to discontinue; to end; to quit\nto cancel; to abandon; to give up; to abolish; to abstain; to refrain\nto stop; to stay (e.g. the night); to cease; to put an end to\nto contain; to keep (in position, in place); to limit\nto record (e.g. a fact); to retain" },
	{ "question": "正しい", "answers": [ "ただしい" ], "comment": "right; correct\nproper; righteous; just; honest; truthful; lawful" },
	{ "question": "歯医者", "answers": [ "はいしゃ" ], "comment": "dentist" },
	{ "question": "歴史", "answers": [ "れきし" ], "comment": "history" },
	{ "question": "残る", "answers": [ "のこる" ], "comment": "to remain; to be left" },
	{ "question": "残念", "answers": [ "ざんねん" ], "comment": "deplorable; bad luck; regret; disappointment" },
	{ "question": "比べる", "answers": [ "くらべる" ], "comment": "to compare; to make a comparison\nto compete; to vie" },
	{ "question": "毛", "answers": [ "け", "もう" ], "comment": "hair\nfur; wool\ndown; plumage; feathers\none-thousandth; 0.03 mm (one-thousandth of a sun); 0.01 percent (one-thousandth of a wari); 3.75 milligrams (one-thousandth of a monme)\nold monetary unit (0.0001 yen)" },
	{ "question": "気", "answers": [ "き", "け" ], "comment": "spirit; mind; heart\nnature; disposition\nmotivation; intention\nmood; feelings\nambience; atmosphere; mood\nseeming; giving the appearance of; giving one the feeling of\n-like nature; -like disposition; -ish temperament\nsign; indication; trace; touch; feeling\nsomehow; for some reason; seeming to be" },
	{ "question": "気分", "answers": [ "きぶん" ], "comment": "feeling; mood" },
	{ "question": "気持ち", "answers": [ "きもち" ], "comment": "feeling; sensation; mood\npreparedness; readiness; attitude\nthanks; solicitude; sympathy\njust a little; somewhat; slightly" },
	{ "question": "水泳", "answers": [ "すいえい" ], "comment": "swimming" },
	{ "question": "水道", "answers": [ "すいどう" ], "comment": "water service; water supply" },
	{ "question": "汚れる", "answers": [ "よごれる", "けがれる" ], "comment": "to be violated; to be corrupted; to be polluted; to be stained\nto get dirty; to become dirty\nto become sullied; to become corrupted; to lose one's chastity" },
	{ "question": "決して", "answers": [ "けっして", "けして" ], "comment": "never; by no means; not in the least; in no way" },
	{ "question": "決まる", "answers": [ "きまる" ], "comment": "to be decided; to be settled\nto look good in (clothes)" },
	{ "question": "決める", "answers": [ "きめる" ], "comment": "to decide; to choose; to determine; to make up one's mind; to resolve; to set one's heart on; to settle; to arrange; to set; to appoint; to fix\nto clinch (a victory); to decide (the outcome of a match)\nto persist in doing; to go through with\nto always do; to have made a habit of\nto take for granted; to assume\nto dress up; to dress to kill; to dress to the nines\nto carry out successfully (a move in sports, a pose in dance, etc.); to succeed in doing\nto immobilize with a double-arm lock (in sumo, judo, etc.)\nto eat or drink something; to take illegal drugs" },
	{ "question": "治る", "answers": [ "なおる" ], "comment": "to be cured; to get well; to be healed\nto get mended; to be repaired; to be fixed" },
	{ "question": "泊まる", "answers": [ "とまる" ], "comment": "to stay at (e.g. hotel)\nto be docked; to be berthed; to be moored" },
	{ "question": "法律", "answers": [ "ほうりつ" ], "comment": "law" },
	{ "question": "泣く", "answers": [ "なく" ], "comment": "to cry; to weep; to sob; to howl" },
	{ "question": "注射", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "injection" },
	{ "question": "注意", "answers": [ "ちゅうい" ], "comment": "caution; being careful; attention (heed); warning; advice" },
	{ "question": "泳ぎ方", "answers": [ "およぎかた" ], "comment": "way of swimming" },
	{ "question": "浅い", "answers": [ "あさい" ], "comment": "shallow; superficial\nslight (wound); light (sleep); pale (colour); inadequate (knowledge)\nshort (time); early; young" },
	{ "question": "海岸", "answers": [ "かいがん" ], "comment": "coast; beach" },
	{ "question": "消しゴム", "answers": [ "けしゴム" ], "comment": "eraser; India rubber" },
	{ "question": "深い", "answers": [ "ふかい" ], "comment": "deep\nprofound\ndense; thick\nclose (relationship)\nintense; strong\nlate" },
	{ "question": "済む", "answers": [ "すむ" ], "comment": "to finish; to end; to be completed\nto merely result in something less severe than expected\nto feel at ease\nto feel unease or guilt for troubling someone; to be sorry" },
	{ "question": "港", "answers": [ "みなと" ], "comment": "harbour; harbor; port\nharbour" },
	{ "question": "湖", "answers": [ "みずうみ" ], "comment": "lake\nlake (in place names)" },
	{ "question": "湯", "answers": [ "ゆ" ], "comment": "hot water\nhot bath; hot spring\nmolten iron\nsoup" },
	{ "question": "漫画", "answers": [ "まんが" ], "comment": "cartoon; comic; comic strip" },
	{ "question": "火事", "answers": [ "かじ" ], "comment": "fire; conflagration" },
	{ "question": "点", "answers": [ "てん" ], "comment": "dot; point; mark\ngidayuu musicians (in kabuki)\nspot; mark\npoint; dot\nmark (e.g. in exam); score; points\ncomma\naspect; matter; respect\ncounter for goods, items, articles of clothing, works of art, etc.\ndot; point; mark\ntip; gratuity\na little; paltry; piddling; mere" },
	{ "question": "無くなる", "answers": [ "なくなる" ], "comment": "to be lost (e.g. luggage); to be missing\nto be used up; to be run out; to be exhausted; to be consumed; to be reduced to zero; to not occur any more\nto disappear (e.g. pain); to be lost (e.g. a dream, confidence)" },
	{ "question": "無理", "answers": [ "むり" ], "comment": "unreasonable; unnatural; unjustifiable\nimpossible\nforcible; forced; compulsory\nexcessive (work, etc.); immoderate\nto work too hard; to try too hard\nirrational" },
	{ "question": "焼く", "answers": [ "やく" ], "comment": "to burn\nto roast; to broil; to grill; to bake; to toast; to barbecue\nto heat; to heat up\nto make (charcoal, pottery, bricks, etc.); to bake; to fire; to burn\nto tan (i.e. suntan); to burn\nto print (a photo); to burn (an optical disc)\nto be jealous of; to be envious of; to envy" },
	{ "question": "焼ける", "answers": [ "やける" ], "comment": "to burn; to be roasted; to be heated; to be sunburnt; to fade (in the sun); to glow red (i.e. of the sky at sunset)\nto be jealous; to be envious" },
	{ "question": "熱", "answers": [ "ねつ" ], "comment": "heat\nfever; temperature\nzeal; passion; enthusiasm\nmania; craze; rage" },
	{ "question": "片付ける", "answers": [ "かたづける" ], "comment": "to tidy up; to put in order; to straighten up; to put away\nto settle (problem); to clear (dispute)\nto finish; to bring something to an end\nto marry off (e.g. a daughter)\nto do away with someone; to bump someone off" },
	{ "question": "特に", "answers": [ "とくに" ], "comment": "particularly; especially" },
	{ "question": "特別", "answers": [ "とくべつ" ], "comment": "special" },
	{ "question": "特急", "answers": [ "とっきゅう" ], "comment": "limited express (train, faster than an express)\ngreat hurry" },
	{ "question": "珍しい", "answers": [ "めずらしい" ], "comment": "unusual; rare; curious\nnew; novel\nfine (e.g. gift)" },
	{ "question": "理由", "answers": [ "りゆう" ], "comment": "reason; pretext; motive" },
	{ "question": "生活", "answers": [ "せいかつ" ], "comment": "living; life (one's daily existence); livelihood" },
	{ "question": "生産", "answers": [ "せいさん" ], "comment": "production; manufacture\nlive birth" },
	{ "question": "用", "answers": [ "よう" ], "comment": "business; task; errand; engagement\nuse; purpose\nfor the use of ...; used for ...; made for ...\ncall of nature; excretion" },
	{ "question": "用事", "answers": [ "ようじ" ], "comment": "tasks; things to do; errand; business (to take care of); affairs; engagement" },
	{ "question": "用意", "answers": [ "ようい" ], "comment": "preparation; arrangements; provision; getting ready; laying out (e.g. a meal)" },
	{ "question": "田舎", "answers": [ "いなか" ], "comment": "rural area; countryside; the sticks\nhometown\ncountry; country home" },
	{ "question": "申し上げる", "answers": [ "もうしあげる" ], "comment": "to say; to tell; to state; to express; to offer; to extend (greetings, congratulations, etc.)\nto do" },
	{ "question": "申す", "answers": [ "もうす" ], "comment": "to say; to be called\nto do" },
	{ "question": "男性", "answers": [ "だんせい" ], "comment": "man; male\nmasculine gender" },
	{ "question": "留守", "answers": [ "るす" ], "comment": "absence; being away from home\nhouse-sitting; house-sitter\nbeing left unattended to (of one's studies, etc.); neglecting" },
	{ "question": "番組", "answers": [ "ばんぐみ" ], "comment": "program (e.g. TV); programme" },
	{ "question": "畳", "answers": [ "たたみ" ], "comment": "counter for tatami mats\nmeasure of room size (in mat units)\ntatami mat; Japanese straw floor coverings\nfolding paper-case; kimono wrapping paper" },
	{ "question": "発音", "answers": [ "はつおん" ], "comment": "pronunciation" },
	{ "question": "皆", "answers": [ "みな", "みんな" ], "comment": "all; everyone; everybody\neverything" },
	{ "question": "盗む", "answers": [ "ぬすむ" ], "comment": "to steal" },
	{ "question": "盛ん", "answers": [ "さかん" ], "comment": "popular\nprosperous\nenthusiastic\nenergetic; vigorous" },
	{ "question": "直す", "answers": [ "なおす" ], "comment": "to cure; to heal\nto fix; to correct; to repair\nto do over again (after -masu base of verb)\nto replace; to put back as it was\nto convert (into a different state); to transform" },
	{ "question": "直る", "answers": [ "なおる" ], "comment": "to be cured; to get well; to be healed\nto get mended; to be repaired; to be fixed" },
	{ "question": "真ん中", "answers": [ "まんなか" ], "comment": "middle; centre; center; mid-way" },
	{ "question": "眠い", "answers": [ "ねむい" ], "comment": "sleepy; drowsy; somnolent" },
	{ "question": "眠る", "answers": [ "ねむる" ], "comment": "to sleep (not necessarily lying down)\nto die\nto lie idle (e.g. of resources); to be dormant; to be unused\nto close one's eyes" },
	{ "question": "着物", "answers": [ "きもの" ], "comment": "clothing; clothes\nkimono (or other trad. Japanese clothing)" },
	{ "question": "知らせる", "answers": [ "しらせる" ], "comment": "to notify; to advise; to inform" },
	{ "question": "石", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "stone\ngem; jewel\nmeasure of volume (approx. 180.39 liters, 6.37 cub. ft.)\nmeasure of a Japanese-style boat's loading capacity (approx. 278.26 liters)" },
	{ "question": "砂", "answers": [ "すな" ], "comment": "sand; grit\ngold dust; silver dust" },
	{ "question": "研究", "answers": [ "けんきゅう" ], "comment": "study; research; investigation" },
	{ "question": "研究室", "answers": [ "けんきゅうしつ" ], "comment": "laboratory\nseminar room\nprofessor's office" },
	{ "question": "硬い", "answers": [ "かたい" ], "comment": "hard; solid; tough\nstiff; tight; wooden; unpolished (e.g. writing)\nstrong; firm (not viscous or easily moved)\nsafe; steady; honest; steadfast\nobstinate; stubborn\nbookish; formal; stuffy" },
	{ "question": "確か", "answers": [ "たしか" ], "comment": "sure; certain; positive; definite\nreliable; trustworthy; safe; sound; firm; accurate; correct; exact\nIf I'm not mistaken; If I remember correctly; If I remember rightly" },
	{ "question": "社会", "answers": [ "しゃかい" ], "comment": "society; public; community; the world\nsocial studies" },
	{ "question": "社長", "answers": [ "しゃちょう" ], "comment": "company president; manager; director" },
	{ "question": "祈る", "answers": [ "いのる" ], "comment": "to pray; to wish" },
	{ "question": "祖母", "answers": [ "そぼ" ], "comment": "grandmother" },
	{ "question": "祖父", "answers": [ "そふ" ], "comment": "grandfather\nold man\nkyogen mask used for the role of an old man" },
	{ "question": "神社", "answers": [ "じんじゃ" ], "comment": "Shinto shrine" },
	{ "question": "科学", "answers": [ "かがく" ], "comment": "science" },
	{ "question": "移る", "answers": [ "うつる" ], "comment": "to move (house); to transfer (department)\nto change the target of interest or concern\nto elapse (passage of time)\nto be permeated by a colour or scent\nto be infected; to be contagious; to spread (as in fire)" },
	{ "question": "空く", "answers": [ "あく", "すく" ], "comment": "to become less crowded; to thin out; to get empty\nto be hungry\nto open (e.g. doors)\nto open (e.g. business, etc.)\nto be empty\nto be vacant; to be available; to be free\nto be open (e.g. neckline, etc.)\nto have been opened (of one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto come to an end\nto open (one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto have a hole; to form a gap; to have an interval (between events)" },
	{ "question": "空気", "answers": [ "くうき" ], "comment": "air; atmosphere\nmood; situation\nsomeone with no presence; someone who doesn't stand out at all" },
	{ "question": "空港", "answers": [ "くうこう" ], "comment": "airport" },
	{ "question": "立てる", "answers": [ "たてる" ], "comment": "to stand up; to put up; to set up; to erect; to raise\nto thrust into; to bury into; to dig into\nto make (a noise); to start (a rumour); to raise (a cloud of dust, etc.); to cause\nto make; to establish; to set up; to develop; to formulate\nto put up (a political candidate); to make (one's leader)\nto treat with respect; to give (someone) their due; to make (someone) look good; to avoid embarrassing (someone)\nto sharpen; to make clear\nto shut; to close\nto make tea (matcha); to perform the tea ceremony\nto divide by\nto do ... vigorously" },
	{ "question": "競争", "answers": [ "きょうそう" ], "comment": "competition; contest\nto compete" },
	{ "question": "笑う", "answers": [ "わらう" ], "comment": "to laugh\nto smile\nto sneer; to ridicule\nto be dumbfounded; to be flabbergasted" },
	{ "question": "答え", "answers": [ "こたえ" ], "comment": "answer; reply; response; solution" },
	{ "question": "簡単", "answers": [ "かんたん" ], "comment": "simple; easy; uncomplicated\nbrief; quick; light" },
	{ "question": "米", "answers": [ "こめ" ], "comment": "metre; meter\nmeter (i.e. a gauge); gauge\n(husked grains of) rice\n88 years old\nAmerica; USA" },
	{ "question": "糸", "answers": [ "いと" ], "comment": "thread; yarn; string\nthread\n0.001; one ten-thousandth" },
	{ "question": "約束", "answers": [ "やくそく" ], "comment": "promise; agreement; arrangement; one's word; contract; pact; appointment; engagement; date\nconvention; rule\ndestiny; fate" },
	{ "question": "細かい", "answers": [ "こまかい" ], "comment": "small\nfine; minute\nminor; trivial\nsensitive; attentive" },
	{ "question": "紹介", "answers": [ "しょうかい" ], "comment": "introduction; presentation; referral; listing" },
	{ "question": "終わり", "answers": [ "おわり" ], "comment": "the end" },
	{ "question": "経済", "answers": [ "けいざい" ], "comment": "economics; business; finance; economy" },
	{ "question": "続く", "answers": [ "つづく" ], "comment": "to continue; to last; to go on\nto continue (without a break); to be unbroken\nto occur again and again\nto lead to; to connect to; to adjoin\nto come after; to follow; to succeed; to rank next to\nto hold out; to keep; to last" },
	{ "question": "続ける", "answers": [ "つづける" ], "comment": "to continue; to keep up; to keep on" },
	{ "question": "線", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "line; stripe; stria\nline (e.g. telephone line); wire\nray (e.g. X-ray); beam\nline (e.g. of a railroad); track; route; lane\noutline; contours; form\nlevel\ndivision\nline (of action); position; approach; policy; principle\nimpression one leaves; air one gives off" },
	{ "question": "美しい", "answers": [ "うつくしい" ], "comment": "beautiful; lovely" },
	{ "question": "美術館", "answers": [ "びじゅつかん" ], "comment": "art gallery; art museum" },
	{ "question": "習慣", "answers": [ "しゅうかん" ], "comment": "habit\ncustom; cultural practice" },
	{ "question": "考える", "answers": [ "かんがえる" ], "comment": "to think about; to take into consideration\nto ponder; to reflect; to try to come at a conclusion; to think over (something)\nto intend; to decide (to do); to plan\nto come up with; to devise; to scheme\nto predict; to anticipate; to expect\nto suspect; to doubt\nto consider (somebody to be something); to look on" },
	{ "question": "聞こえる", "answers": [ "きこえる" ], "comment": "to be heard; to be audible\nto be said to be; to be reputed" },
	{ "question": "育てる", "answers": [ "そだてる" ], "comment": "to raise; to rear; to bring up\nto train; to teach; to educate\nto promote the growth of; to nurture; to foster; to develop" },
	{ "question": "背中", "answers": [ "せなか" ], "comment": "back (of body)" },
	{ "question": "腕", "answers": [ "うで" ], "comment": "arm\nskill; efforts; ability\narm (esp. upper arm)\ncounter used to measure the thickness of round objects" },
	{ "question": "自由", "answers": [ "じゆう" ], "comment": "freedom; liberty; as it pleases you" },
	{ "question": "致す", "answers": [ "いたす" ], "comment": "to do" },
	{ "question": "興味", "answers": [ "きょうみ" ], "comment": "interest (in something); curiosity (about something); zest (for)" },
	{ "question": "船", "answers": [ "ふね" ], "comment": "ship; boat; watercraft; vessel; steamship\ntank; tub; vat; trough\ncounter for boat-shaped containers (e.g. of sashimi)" },
	{ "question": "花見", "answers": [ "はなみ" ], "comment": "cherry blossom viewing; flower viewing" },
	{ "question": "花瓶", "answers": [ "かびん" ], "comment": "(flower) vase\nvase used to hold flower offerings (often made of gilded copper)" },
	{ "question": "苦い", "answers": [ "にがい" ], "comment": "bitter" },
	{ "question": "草", "answers": [ "くさ" ], "comment": "grass; weed; herb; thatch\nninja\nnot genuine; substandard\nlaughter; LOL\ndraft; rough copy\ncursive script; \"grass\" kanji" },
	{ "question": "落とす", "answers": [ "おとす" ], "comment": "to drop; to lose; to let fall; to shed (light); to cast (one's gaze); to pour in (liquid); to leave behind\nto clean off (dirt, makeup, paint, etc.); to remove (e.g. stains or facial hair); to lose; to spend money at a certain place; to omit; to leave out; to secretly let escape\nto lose (a match); to reject (an applicant); to fail (a course); to defeat (in an election)\nto lower (e.g. shoulders or voice); to lessen (e.g. production or body weight); to worsen (quality); to reduce (e.g. rank or popularity); to speak badly of; to make light of; to fall into straitened circumstances\nto fall into (e.g. a dilemma or sin); to make one's own; to have one's bid accepted; to force surrender; to take (e.g. an enemy camp or castle); to forcefully convince; to press for a confession; to deal with\nto download; to copy from a computer to another medium\nto make someone swoon (judo)\nto finish a story (e.g. with the punch line)\nto finish (a period, e.g. of fasting)" },
	{ "question": "落ちる", "answers": [ "おちる" ], "comment": "to fall down; to drop; to fall (e.g. rain); to sink (e.g. sun or moon); to fall onto (e.g. light or one's gaze); to be used in a certain place (e.g. money)\nto be omitted; to be missing\nto decrease; to sink\nto fail (e.g. exam or class); to lose (contest, election, etc.)\nto crash; to degenerate; to degrade; to fall behind\nto become indecent (of a conversation)\nto be ruined; to go under\nto fade; to come out (e.g. a stain); to come off (e.g. makeup); to be removed (e.g. illness, possessing spirit, name on a list)\nto fall (into someone's hands); to become someone's possession\nto fall (into a trap); to fall (for a trick)\nto give in; to give up; to confess; to flee\nto fall; to be defeated; to surrender\nto come to (in the end); to end in\nto fall (in love, asleep, etc.)\nto swoon (judo)\nto consent; to understand\nto crash; to freeze\nto die\nto move to the depths" },
	{ "question": "葉", "answers": [ "は" ], "comment": "leaf\ncounter for leaves, pieces of paper, etc.\ncounter for boats" },
	{ "question": "虫", "answers": [ "むし" ], "comment": "insect; bug; cricket; moth; worm" },
	{ "question": "血", "answers": [ "ち" ], "comment": "blood; consanguinity" },
	{ "question": "行う", "answers": [ "おこなう" ], "comment": "to perform; to do; to conduct oneself; to carry out" },
	{ "question": "表", "answers": [ "おもて", "ひょう" ], "comment": "surface\nface (i.e. the visible side of an object)\nfront (of a building, etc.); obverse side (i.e. \"head\") of a coin\noutside; exterior\nappearance\npublic\nfirst half (of an inning); top (of an inning)\ncover (for tatami mats, etc.)\nforeground\ntable (e.g. Table 1); chart; list" },
	{ "question": "裏", "answers": [ "うら" ], "comment": "bottom (or another side that is hidden from view); undersurface; opposite side; reverse side\nrear; back; behind (the house)\nlining; inside\nout of sight; behind the scenes; in the shadows\nproof\nopposite (of a prediction, common sense, etc.)\ninverse (of a hypothesis, etc.)\nbottom (of an inning); last half (of an inning)" },
	{ "question": "複雑", "answers": [ "ふくざつ" ], "comment": "complex; complicated; mixed (feelings)" },
	{ "question": "西洋", "answers": [ "せいよう" ], "comment": "the west; Western countries" },
	{ "question": "見つかる", "answers": [ "みつかる" ], "comment": "to be found; to be discovered" },
	{ "question": "見つける", "answers": [ "みつける" ], "comment": "to discover; to find (e.g. an error in a book); to come across; to detect; to spot\nto locate; to find (e.g. something missing); to find fault\nto be used to seeing; to be familiar with" },
	{ "question": "見物", "answers": [ "けんぶつ", "みもの" ], "comment": "sightseeing; watching; viewing\nsightseer; watcher; spectator\nsight; attraction; spectacle; something worth seeing" },
	{ "question": "規則", "answers": [ "きそく" ], "comment": "rules; regulations; conventions" },
	{ "question": "親", "answers": [ "おや" ], "comment": "parent; parents\ndealer (in cards, mahjong, etc.)\nfounder\n(pet) owner\nintimacy; closeness; friendliness\nclose relative\npro- (e.g. pro-American, pro-Japanese, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "親切", "answers": [ "しんせつ" ], "comment": "kindness; gentleness" },
	{ "question": "触る", "answers": [ "さわる" ], "comment": "to touch; to feel" },
	{ "question": "訪ねる", "answers": [ "たずねる" ], "comment": "to visit; to call on; to pay a visit to" },
	{ "question": "訳", "answers": [ "わけ", "やく" ], "comment": "conclusion from reasoning, judgement or calculation based on something read or heard; reason; cause; meaning; circumstances; situation\ntranslation; version (e.g. \"English version\")" },
	{ "question": "試合", "answers": [ "しあい" ], "comment": "match; game; bout; contest" },
	{ "question": "試験", "answers": [ "しけん" ], "comment": "examination; exam; test\ntrial; experiment; test" },
	{ "question": "説明", "answers": [ "せつめい" ], "comment": "explanation; exposition" },
	{ "question": "課長", "answers": [ "かちょう" ], "comment": "section manager; section chief" },
	{ "question": "調べる", "answers": [ "しらべる" ], "comment": "to examine; to investigate; to check up; to sense; to study; to inquire; to search" },
	{ "question": "講堂", "answers": [ "こうどう" ], "comment": "auditorium; lecture hall" },
	{ "question": "講義", "answers": [ "こうぎ" ], "comment": "lecture" },
	{ "question": "警察", "answers": [ "けいさつ" ], "comment": "police\npolice officer\npolice station" },
	{ "question": "負ける", "answers": [ "まける" ], "comment": "to lose; to be defeated\nto succumb; to give in; to surrender; to yield\nto be inferior to\nto break out in a rash due to (e.g. lacquer, shaving, etc.)\nto reduce the price; to give a discount; to throw in (something extra) for free" },
	{ "question": "貿易", "answers": [ "ぼうえき" ], "comment": "trade (foreign)" },
	{ "question": "贈り物", "answers": [ "おくりもの" ], "comment": "present; gift" },
	{ "question": "赤ん坊", "answers": [ "あかんぼう" ], "comment": "baby; infant" },
	{ "question": "起こす", "answers": [ "おこす" ], "comment": "to raise; to raise up; to set up; to pick up\nto wake; to wake up; to waken; to awaken\nto cause; to bring about; to lead to; to trigger; to give rise to; to create; to generate (e.g. heat, electricity); to produce\nto start; to begin; to launch; to establish; to found; to set up; to open\nto plough; to plow; to till\nto fall ill with\nto transcribe; to write down (what is spoken)\nto turn over (a card)" },
	{ "question": "趣味", "answers": [ "しゅみ" ], "comment": "hobby; pastime\ntastes; preference; liking" },
	{ "question": "足す", "answers": [ "たす" ], "comment": "to add (numbers)\nto add (something); to top up (with something)\nto take care of (e.g. one's business)" },
	{ "question": "足りる", "answers": [ "たりる" ], "comment": "to be sufficient; to be enough\nto be worth doing; to be worthy\nto be sufficient; to answer; to do" },
	{ "question": "踊り", "answers": [ "おどり" ], "comment": "dance" },
	{ "question": "踊る", "answers": [ "おどる" ], "comment": "to dance (orig. a hopping dance)" },
	{ "question": "辞典", "answers": [ "じてん" ], "comment": "dictionary" },
	{ "question": "込む", "answers": [ "こむ" ], "comment": "to be crowded; to be packed\nto be complex\nto go into; to put into; to remain (seated); to be plunged into (silence); to do thoroughly\nto do intently\nto continue in the same state" },
	{ "question": "迎える", "answers": [ "むかえる" ], "comment": "to go out to meet\nto receive; to welcome; to greet; to salute; to hail; to reach; to approach; to enter (a phase, era, etc.)\nto accept (e.g. as a member of a group or family)\nto call for; to summon; to invite\nto approach (a certain time, a point in one's life, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "近所", "answers": [ "きんじょ" ], "comment": "neighbourhood; neighborhood" },
	{ "question": "返事", "answers": [ "へんじ" ], "comment": "reply; answer; response" },
	{ "question": "退院", "answers": [ "たいいん" ], "comment": "leaving hospital; discharge from hospital" },
	{ "question": "送る", "answers": [ "おくる" ], "comment": "to send (a thing); to dispatch; to despatch; to transmit\nto take or escort (a person somewhere); to see off (a person)\nto bid farewell (to the departed); to bury\nto spend (time); to live one's life\nto pass (down the line)\nto affix okurigana" },
	{ "question": "逃げる", "answers": [ "にげる" ], "comment": "to escape; to run away" },
	{ "question": "途中", "answers": [ "とちゅう" ], "comment": "on the way; en route\nin the middle of; midway" },
	{ "question": "通う", "answers": [ "かよう" ], "comment": "to go to and from (a place); to go back and forth between; to run between (e.g. bus, train, etc.); to ply between\nto go to (school, work, etc.); to attend; to commute; to frequent\nto circulate (e.g. blood, electricity); to be communicated (e.g. thought)\nto resemble" },
	{ "question": "通る", "answers": [ "とおる" ], "comment": "to go by; to go past; to go along; to travel along; to pass through; to use (a road); to take (a route); to go via; to go by way of\nto run (between); to operate (between); to connect\nto go indoors; to go into a room; to be admitted; to be shown in; to be ushered in; to come in\nto penetrate; to pierce; to skewer; to go through; to come through\nto permeate; to soak into; to spread throughout\nto carry (e.g. of a voice); to reach far\nto be passed on (e.g. of a customer's order to the kitchen); to be relayed; to be conveyed\nto pass (a test, a bill in the House, etc.); to be approved; to be accepted\nto go by (a name); to be known as; to be accepted as; to have a reputation for\nto be coherent; to be logical; to be reasonable; to be comprehensible; to be understandable; to make sense\nto get across (e.g. of one's point); to be understood\nto be straight (e.g. wood grain)\nto be well-informed; to be wise\nto do ... completely; to do ... thoroughly" },
	{ "question": "連絡", "answers": [ "れんらく" ], "comment": "to contact; to get in touch\ncontacting; getting in touch; communication; call; message\nconnection; coordination; junction\nintercalary; intercalaris; internuncial" },
	{ "question": "進む", "answers": [ "すすむ" ], "comment": "to advance; to go forward\nto precede; to go ahead (of)\nto make progress; to improve\nto deepen; to heighten\nto be fast (of a clock); to be ahead\nto do of one's own free will\nto grow wild; to run to waste" },
	{ "question": "遅れる", "answers": [ "おくれる" ], "comment": "to be late; to be delayed; to fall behind schedule; to be overdue" },
	{ "question": "遊び", "answers": [ "あそび" ], "comment": "playing\nplay (margin between on and off, gap before pressing button or lever has an effect)" },
	{ "question": "運ぶ", "answers": [ "はこぶ" ], "comment": "to carry; to transport; to move; to convey\nto come; to go\nto wield (a tool, etc.); to use\nto go (well, etc.); to proceed; to progress" },
	{ "question": "運転手", "answers": [ "うんてんしゅ" ], "comment": "driver; chauffeur" },
	{ "question": "過ぎる", "answers": [ "すぎる" ], "comment": "to pass through; to pass by; to go beyond\nto pass (i.e. of time); to elapse\nto have expired; to have ended; to be over\nto exceed; to surpass; to be above\nto be no more than ...\nto be excessive; to be too much; to be too ...\nto go by; to cross; to pass by; to float across" },
	{ "question": "道具", "answers": [ "どうぐ" ], "comment": "tool; implement; instrument; utensil; apparatus; device\nmeans" },
	{ "question": "適当", "answers": [ "てきとう" ], "comment": "suitable; proper; appropriate; adequate; fit\nnoncommittal; vague; equivocal; unserious; irresponsible" },
	{ "question": "選ぶ", "answers": [ "えらぶ" ], "comment": "to choose; to select" },
	{ "question": "郊外", "answers": [ "こうがい" ], "comment": "suburb; outskirts" },
	{ "question": "部長", "answers": [ "ぶちょう" ], "comment": "head (chief, director) of a section or department\nhead of a (school) club; head of a (school) team" },
	{ "question": "都", "answers": [ "と", "みやこ" ], "comment": "capital; metropolis\nmetropolitan; municipal" },
	{ "question": "都合", "answers": [ "つごう" ], "comment": "circumstances; condition; convenience\nto arrange; to manage\nto lend money; to raise money\nin all; in total; all told" },
	{ "question": "金持ち", "answers": [ "かねもち" ], "comment": "rich person" },
	{ "question": "開く", "answers": [ "ひらく", "あく" ], "comment": "to open; to undo; to unseal; to unpack\nto bloom; to unfold; to spread out\nto open (for business, e.g. in the morning)\nto be wide (gap, etc.); to widen\nto hold (meeting, etc.); to give; to open\nto found (nation, dynasty, sect, etc.); to open (a new business); to set up; to establish; to start\nto open (ports, borders, etc.)\nto open (an account)\nto open up (new land, path, etc.); to clear; to develop\nto open (a file, etc.)\nto extract (root); to reduce (equation)\nto cut open (fish)\nto change (kanji into hiragana)\nto flare (e.g. skirt)\nto slacken (into a poor posture)\nto open (e.g. doors)\nto open (e.g. business, etc.)\nto be empty\nto be vacant; to be available; to be free\nto be open (e.g. neckline, etc.)\nto have been opened (of one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto come to an end\nto open (one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto have a hole; to form a gap; to have an interval (between events)" },
	{ "question": "間に合う", "answers": [ "まにあう" ], "comment": "to be in time for\nto serve (suit, meet) the purpose; to be good enough; to be enough" },
	{ "question": "間違える", "answers": [ "まちがえる" ], "comment": "to make a mistake (in); to commit an error (e.g. in calculation)\nto confuse; to mistake something for something else" },
	{ "question": "関係", "answers": [ "かんけい" ], "comment": "relation; relationship; connection\nparticipation; involvement; concern\ninfluence; effect\nsexual relations; sexual relationship\nrelated to ...; connected to ..." },
	{ "question": "降り出す", "answers": [ "ふりだす" ], "comment": "to begin to rain; to begin to snow" },
	{ "question": "集まる", "answers": [ "あつまる" ], "comment": "to gather; to collect; to assemble" },
	{ "question": "集める", "answers": [ "あつめる" ], "comment": "to collect; to assemble; to gather" },
	{ "question": "電報", "answers": [ "でんぽう" ], "comment": "telegram" },
	{ "question": "電灯", "answers": [ "でんとう" ], "comment": "electric light" },
	{ "question": "非常に", "answers": [ "ひじょうに" ], "comment": "very; extremely; exceedingly" },
	{ "question": "音", "answers": [ "おと", "ね" ], "comment": "sound; noise; report\nnote\nfame\nChinese-derived character reading" },
	{ "question": "飛行場", "answers": [ "ひこうじょう" ], "comment": "airfield; airport" },
	{ "question": "食料品", "answers": [ "しょくりょうひん" ], "comment": "foodstuff; groceries" },
	{ "question": "首", "answers": [ "くび", "こうべ" ], "comment": "neck\nhead\ndismissal; discharge; firing (from a job)" },
	{ "question": "駐車場", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃじょう" ], "comment": "parking lot; parking place" },
	{ "question": "騒ぐ", "answers": [ "さわぐ" ], "comment": "to make noise; to make racket; to be noisy\nto rustle; to swoosh\nto make merry\nto clamor; to clamour; to make a fuss; to kick up a fuss\nto lose one's cool; to panic; to act flustered\nto feel tense; to be uneasy; to be excited" },
	{ "question": "高校", "answers": [ "こうこう" ], "comment": "senior high school; high school" },
	{ "question": "高校生", "answers": [ "こうこうせい" ], "comment": "senior high school student" },
	{ "question": "歯", "answers": [ "は" ], "comment": "tooth\n(one's) age" },
	{ "question": "横", "answers": [ "よこ" ], "comment": "horizontal (as opposed to vertical); lying down\nside-to-side (as opposed to front-to-back); width; breadth\nside (of a box, etc.)\nbeside; aside; next to\nunconnected" },
	{ "question": "橋", "answers": [ "はし" ], "comment": "bridge" },
	{ "question": "切符", "answers": [ "きっぷ" ], "comment": "ticket" },
	{ "question": "吸う", "answers": [ "すう" ], "comment": "to smoke; to breathe in; to inhale\nto suck; to sip; to slurp\nto absorb; to soak up\nto kiss" },
	{ "question": "吹く", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "to blow (e.g. wind); to play a wind instrument\nto emit; to spout\nto whistle\nto laugh; to burst into laughter\nto smelt; to mint\nto brag; to talk big" },
	{ "question": "咲く", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "to bloom" },
	{ "question": "地下鉄", "answers": [ "ちかてつ" ], "comment": "underground train; subway" },
	{ "question": "字引", "answers": [ "じびき" ], "comment": "dictionary" },
	{ "question": "差す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "to shine\nto be visible\nto be tinged with\nto rise (of water levels); to flow in\nto be felt (i.e. as an emotion); to come over one\nto hold up (an umbrella, etc.); to put up; to raise\nto extend one's arm straight ahead (in dance)\nto insert; to put in\nto wear (a sword) in one's belt; to wear at one's side; to carry under one's arm\nto insert one's arm under an opponent's arm\nto pole (a boat)\nto pour; to add (liquid); to serve (drinks)\nto put on (lipstick, etc.); to apply; to colour; to dye\nto light (a fire); to burn\nto shut; to close; to lock; to fasten\nto stop in the midst of; to leave undone" },
	{ "question": "座る", "answers": [ "すわる" ], "comment": "to sit; to squat\nto assume (a position)\nto hold steady; to hold still" },
	{ "question": "庭", "answers": [ "にわ" ], "comment": "garden; yard; courtyard\nfield (of action); area" },
	{ "question": "戸", "answers": [ "と" ], "comment": "door (esp. Japanese-style)\nshutter; window shutter\nentrance (to a home)\nnarrows\ncounter for houses, households, apartments, etc." },
	{ "question": "短い", "answers": [ "みじかい" ], "comment": "short" },
	{ "question": "緑", "answers": [ "みどり" ], "comment": "green\ngreenery (esp. fresh verdure)" },
	{ "question": "角", "answers": [ "かど", "つの", "かく" ], "comment": "angle\nsquare (or cube)\nbishop\nthird degree (of the Japanese & Chinese pentatonic scale)\nChinese \"horn\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\njiao (monetary unit of China; one-tenth of a yuan)\ncorner (e.g. desk, pavement)\nedge\nhorn\ncorner; nook; recess\ndownstage right (on a noh stage)" },
	{ "question": "豚肉", "answers": [ "ぶたにく" ], "comment": "pork" },
	{ "question": "軽い", "answers": [ "かるい" ], "comment": "light (i.e. not heavy); feeling light (i.e. offering little resistance, moving easily)\nlight (i.e. of foot); nimble; agile\nnon-serious; minor; unimportant; trivial\nslight; small; gentle; soft\neasy; simple\nindiscriminate" },
	{ "question": "辺", "answers": [ "へん", "ほとり" ], "comment": "area; vicinity; region\nside; edge\ncircumstances\nsurrounding area\nshore (of the sea)\nsuffix used as a rough indicator of location, direction, time, etc." },
	{ "question": "郵便局", "answers": [ "ゆうびんきょく" ], "comment": "post office" },
	{ "question": "野菜", "answers": [ "やさい" ], "comment": "vegetable" },
	{ "question": "雑誌", "answers": [ "ざっし" ], "comment": "journal; magazine; periodical" },
	{ "question": "黄色", "answers": [ "きいろ" ], "comment": "yellow; amber" },
	{ "question": "黄色い", "answers": [ "きいろい" ], "comment": "yellow\nhigh-pitched (voice); shrill" },
	{ "question": "靴", "answers": [ "くつ" ], "comment": "shoes; boots; footwear; footgear" },
	{ "question": "靴下", "answers": [ "くつした" ], "comment": "socks; sock; stockings; stocking" },
	{ "question": "高等学校", "answers": [ "こうとうがっこう" ], "comment": "senior high school; high school" }
]
}
